Emilio Campos Jr.

Chicago, IL | (815) 543-8461 | ecampos.jr54@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

As a former lawyer, I managed over 60 cases at once and collaborated with multiple teams. I analyzed 500 pages of detailed information per case and researched case law to resolve issues. I applied these skills to develop applications in my software engineering boot camp: I collaborated with teams, analyzed problems, and researched to debug any issues. As a software engineer, I will continue to apply these problem-solving skills that were essential to my work as an attorney.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Express | React | Node | JavaScript | HTML | CSS | MongoDB | Material UI | OAuth | Git | OOP | Firebase Figma | Passport.js | SQL | NoSQL | PostgreSQL | APIs | Python | Flask | Django | Tailwind CSS

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Video Game Library | Code | App

- Designed a React UI single page application to allow users to perform CRUD functions on games and share them
- Implemented Google sign-in via an OAuth 2.0 authorization framework and a Passport.js authentication middleware
- Added a game sharing feature between users and regulated CRUD functionality based on Google credentials
- Managed data for users' games in a MongoDB database and imported API game data via a third-party REST API

GitRipped | Code | App

- React UI single page application that contains preset exercises and allows users to customize their own
- Built the backend, including the model, view, and controller layers to organize data for each exercise
- Connected this SPA to a third-party REST API to import exercises and render data via the fetch method
- Extensively engaged in pair programming, debugging and version control best practices

Ollivanders | Code | App

- Utilized JavaScript functions and loops, Mongoose, Express, and EJS to create a wand inventory
- Implemented RESTful routes and full CRUD functions to allow the user to view, edit and add custom wands

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer / The Collab Lab

02/2024 - Present

- Collaborate with a team of developers to build a Smart Shopping List Application (Firebase, React, and JavaScript)
- Review team members' pull requests and provide feedback to prevent bugs in production
- Present code to senior engineers for review to ensure best coding practices and design patterns

Quality Assurance Reviewer / Remotasks

12/2023 - Present

- Evaluate inputs to an AI chatbot and provide feedback to promote AI responses that are accurate and concise
- Assess the quality of the chatbot's responses based upon its adherence to the system's programmed instructions
- Communicate to the QA Lead about all high-level QA issues in order to foster consistent and accurate evaluations

AI Prompt Engineer | Remotasks

08/2023 - 12/2023

- Trained an AI (LLM based) by prompting it with complex legal questions and creating model answers
- Leveraged technical expertise to test edge cases of the learned language model and improve the user experience

Staff Attorney I | Catholic Charities Legal Assistance

06/2021 - 04/2022

- Provided focused legal advice to over 100 self-represented clients based on an "on-the-spot" legal analysis
- Negotiated with multiple stakeholders to reach an optimal case resolution for clients

EDUCATION/AWARDS

All Builders' Welcome Grant Award Sponsored by AWS	11/2023
General Assembly Software Engineering Certification	11/2022
University of Illinois College of Law Juris Doctor	05/2020
Lovola University Chicago Rachelor of Rusiness Administration in Feonomics and Rusiness Management	05/2013